Guide to the H. Paul Castleberry Papers 1940-1983
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Series 8: International Law and Organization; International Relations
  - Subseries 8.5: Country and Area File
    - Russia: Jewish Emigration, 1971-1977 (Box 15, Folder 566)
    - Russia: Strategy and Tactics, Government, 1965-1982 (Box 15, Folder 567)
    - Southern Africa, 1960-1985 (Box 15, Folder 568)
    - Spain, 1946-1982 (Box 15, Folder 569)
    - Vatican, 1952-1984 (Box 15, Folder 570)
    - Vietnam- Southeast Asia, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 571)
    - Yugoslavia, Tito, 1955-1980 (Box 15, Folder 572)
  - Subseries 8.6 Cyprus, Greece and Turkey
    - Cyprus and Greece-Turkish Relations, American Arms Embargo, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 573)
    - Cyprus Clippings, 1960-1964 (Box 15, Folder 574)
    - Cyprus Clippings, 1964-1975 (Box 15, Folder 575)
    - Cyprus Conflict, 1955-1982 (Box 15, Folder 576)
    - Cyprus, Historical Background and Castleberry Article, 1954-1984 (Box 16, Folder 577)
    - Cyprus Issue, 1956-1963 (Box 16, Folder 578)
    - Cyprus Issue, 1956-1964 (Box 16, Folder 579)
    - Cyprus Issue and Greek-Turkish Relations, Pamphlets, 1956-1964 (Box 16, Folder 580)
    - Cyprus Issue and Greek-Turkish Relations, Pamphlets, 1956-1964 (Box 16, Folder 581)
    - Cyprus Manuscript and Clippings, 1964-1967 (Box 16, Folder 582)
    - Cyprus, Spokane Speech, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 583)
    - Greece, Greek-United States Relations, 1963-1985 (Box 16, Folder 584)
    - Turkey, 1960-1982 (Box 16, Folder 585)
    - Turkey and The United Nations, 1963-1979 (Box 16, Folder 586)
    - Turkey: Daily News, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 587)
    - Turkey: Economic Development, 1963-1966 (Box 16, Folder 588)
    - Turkey: Foreign Policy, 1946-1982 (Box 16, Folder 589)
    - Turkey: Government, Politics, The Economy, 1961-1982 (Box 16, Folder 590)
    - Turkey: History, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 591)
    - Turkey: Professor Paul Castleberry's Journal, 1963-1965 (Box 16, Folder 592)
    - Turkey: Riots of 1963, undated (Box 16, Folder 593)
    - Turkey: Turkish Information Office, 1961-1979 (Box 16, Folder 594)
- Series 9: Middle East
  - Aden, South Yemen and the Trucial States, 1964-1973 (Box 16, Folder 595)
  - Afghanistan, 1956-1986 (Box 16, Folder 596)
  - Algeria, 1955-1981 (Box 16, Folder 597)
  - America's Stake in the Middle East, 1956-1982 (Box 16, Folder 598)
  - Antiquities, 1954-1956 (Box 16, Folder 599)
  - Arab Boycott, 1974-1977 (Box 16, Folder 600)
  - Arab Federations, 1958-1980 (Box 16, Folder 601)
  - Arab Information: Agencies, Speakers, Addresses, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 602)
  - Arab-Israeli Dispute, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 603)
  - Arab League, 1956-1982 (Box 17, Folder 604)
  - Arab Nationalism, 1958-1973 (Box 17, Folder 605)
  - Baghdad Pact, 1955-1980 (Box 17, Folder 606)
  - Camp David Negotiations, 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 607)
  - Economic Aid From Arab States, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 608)
  - Economic Interests and Power of the Middle East, 1975-1983 (Box 17, Folder 609)
  - Egypt and the Suez Canal Dispute, 1956-1975 (Box 17, Folder 610)
  - Egypt and the United Arab Republic, 1953-1963 (Box 17, Folder 611)
  - Egypt: Constitutional System, 1954-1978 (Box 17, Folder 612)
  - Egypt: Civil and Political Rights, 1954-1960 (Box 17, Folder 613)
  - Egypt: Economic and Social Change, 1953-1979 (Box 17, Folder 614)
  - Egypt: Foreign Relations, 1954-1984 (Box 17, Folder 615)
  - Egypt: Local Government, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 616)
  - Egypt: Miscellaneous Insights, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 617)
  - Egypt: Moslem Brotherhood, 1953-1954 (Box 17, Folder 618)
  - Egypt: Post-Sadat Era, 1979-1989 (Box 17, Folder 619)
  - Egypt: Public Administration, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 620)
  - Egypt: Public Administration and Personnel, 19531954 (Box 17, Folder 621)
  - Egypt: The Aswan Dam, 1956-1972 (Box 17, Folder 622)
  - Egypt: Wafd Trials, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 623)
  - Gaza, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 624)
  - Iran, 1951-1982 (Box 17, Folder 625)
  - Iran, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 626)
  - Iran, 1979-1990 (Box 17, Folder 627)
  - Iran and the Contras, 1983-1987 (Box 17, Folder 628)
  - Iran: Hostage Rescue Attempt, 1980-1982 (Box 17, Folder 629)
  - Iran: Relations with the United States: United States Interests, 1979-1982 (Box 17, Folder 630)
  - Iran: The Revolution and War, 1978-1983 (Box 17, Folder 631)
  - Iran-Iraq War, 1980-1982 (Box 17, Folder 632)
  - Iraq, 1954-1990 (Box 17, Folder 633)
  - Islam, 1953-198U (Box 17, Folder 634)
  - Israel, 1970-1982 (Box 17, Folder 635)
  - Israel and Lebanon, 1982-1990 (Box 18, Folder 636)
  - Israel and the Invasion of Lebanon, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 637)
  - Israel and the Invasion of Lebanon, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 638)
  - Israel and the Bomb, 1978-1981 (Box 18, Folder 639)
  - Israel: Foreign Relations, Relations with the United States, 1972-1981 (Box 18, Folder 640)
  - Israel: Foreign Relations, Relations with the United States, 1975-1982 (Box 18, Folder 641)
  - Israel: Recognition Issue, 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 642)
  - Israel: The Israel-United States Relationship, 1953-1977 (Box 18, Folder 643)
  - Israel: The Israel-United States Relationship, 1974-1990 (Box 18, Folder 644)
  - Israel versus the Arabs, 1953-1972 (Box 18, Folder 645)
  - Israel versus the Arabs, 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 646)
  - Israeli-Arab War (1956-1969) (Box 18, Folder 647)
  - Israeli-Arab War, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 648)
  - Israeli-Arab War, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 649)
  - Israeli-Arab War, 1973-1975 (Box 18, Folder 650)
  - Jordan, 1956-1982 (Box 18, Folder 651)
  - Jordan-Israel, 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 652)
  - Jordan-Syrian Relations, 1980-1989 (Box 18, Folder 653)
  - Kuwait and Persian Gulf Area, 1958-1980 (Box 18, Folder 654)
  - Lebanon, 1975-1982 (Box 18, Folder 655)
  - Lebanon, 1979-1989 (Box 19, Folder 656)
  - Lebanon, Civil War, 1956-1971 (Box 19, Folder 657)
  - Libya, 1958-1984 (Box 19, Folder 658)
  - Libya, 1984-1987 (Box 19, Folder 659)
  - Libya: Correspondence with H. Paul Castleberry, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 660)
  - Libya: H. Paul Castleberry Trip, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 661)
  - Maghreb, 1964-1972 (Box 19, Folder 662)
  - Middle East, 1952-1957 (Box 19, Folder 663)
  - Middle East, 1956-1979 (Box 19, Folder 664)
  - Middle East Defined, 1952-1960 (Box 19, Folder 665)
  - Middle East: H. Paul Castleberry's Speech to Retired Officers and Kiwanis; developments in the region, 1983-1987 (Box 19, Folder 666)
  - Middle East Peace Process, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 667)
  - Middle East Settlement, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 668)
  - Middle East Speech, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 669)
  - Middle East Speech in Wallace, Idaho, by H. Paul Castleberry, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 670)
  - Morocco, 1952-1981 (Box 19, Folder 671)
  - Nasser, 1955-1973 (Box 19, Folder 672)
  - Oil, 1952-1974 (Box 19, Folder 673)
  - Oil, 1952-1974 (Box 19, Folder 674)
  - Oil, 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 675)
  - Oil, 1977-1980 (Box 19, Folder 676)
  - Oil and Energy, Reading Lists and Primary Sources, 1976-1990 (Box 19, Folder 677)
  - Palestine, 1950-1982 (Box 19, Folder 678)
  - Palestine, 1971-1987 (Box 19, Folder 679)
  - Palestine, Saudi Arabia, and Turkey, 1978-1980 (Box 20, Folder 680)
  - Palestine: The Arab Case, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 681)
  - Palestinians, 1975-1983 (Box 20, Folder 682)
  - Persian Gulf, 1975-1982 (Box 20, Folder 683)
  - Persian Gulf "Crises", 1978-1981 (Box 20, Folder 684)
  - Persian Gulf War and Palestine, 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 685)
  - Refugees: United Nations Relief and Works Agency, 1950-1981 (Box 20, Folder 686)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1955-1984 (Box 20, Folder 687)
  - Saudi Arabia and the Gulf States, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 688)
  - Saudi Arabia: "Foundations A Decade of Development,", 1982 (Box 20, Folder 689)
  - Saudi Arabia: Middle East Arms Package, 1978-1982 (Box 20, Folder 690)
  - Saudi Arabia: Reports to the Congress by the Comptroller General on Economic Cooperation, Military Sales and Oil Production, 1977-1979 (Box 20, Folder 691)
  - Somalia, 1977-1981 (Box 20, Folder 692)
  - Soviet Economic Penetration of the Middle East, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 693)
  - Sudan, 1951-1981 (Box 20, Folder 694)
  - Syria, 1956-1990 (Box 20, Folder 695)
  - Tripartite Declaration of 1950 (Box 20, Folder 696)
  - Tunisia, 1956-1968 (Box 20, Folder 697)
  - Turkey and Greece, Relations with the United States, 1976-1990 (Box 20, Folder 698)
  - United Arab Republic, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 699)
  - United States Policy and the Middle East Crisis, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 700)
  - United States Regional Policy, Mideast, 1978-1981 (Box 20, Folder 701)
  - Yemen, 1963-1986 (Box 20, Folder 702)
  - Zionism, 1953-1983 (Box 20, Folder 703)
  - Zionism, Anti-Zionism; Dissidents, 1955-1977 (Box 20, Folder 704)
- Series 10: United States Foreign Policy
  - Subseries 10.1: General
    - Aggression and Nature of Man, 1968-1972 (Box 20, Folder 705)
    - Alliance for Progress, 1963-1968 (Box 20, Folder 706)
    - Appeasement, 1951-1966 (Box 20, Folder 707)
    - Central America, 1983-1990 (Box 20, Folder 708)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1950-1963 (Box 20, Folder 709)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1963-1970 (Box 20, Folder 710)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1970-1977 (Box 20, Folder 711)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1974-1985 (Box 21, Folder 712)
    - Cold War, 1950-1982 (Box 21, Folder 713)
    - Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe, Helsinki. also: detente and human rights, 1975-1985 (Box 21, Folder 714)
    - Congress and Foreign Policy, 1957-1971 (Box 21, Folder 715)
    - Critique, George Kennan, 1951-1972 (Box 21, Folder 716)
    - Critiques on Recent Diplomacy, 1950-1961 (Box 21, Folder 717)
    - Critiques on Recent Diplomacy, 1957-1982 (Box 21, Folder 718)
    - Cultural and Informational Instruments of United States Foreign Policy, 1975-1982 (Box 21, Folder 719)
    - Deception, 1965-1975 (Box 21, Folder 720)
    - Decision-Making, 1969-1974 (Box 21, Folder 721)
    - Democracy and Foreign Policy, 1948-1964 (Box 21, Folder 722)
    - Detente, 1974-1984 (Box 21, Folder 723)
    - Diplomacy, 1952-1970 (Box 21, Folder 724)
    - Domestic Role: Central Intelligence Agency, Federal Bureau of Investigation, Department of Defense, 1973-1981 (Box 21, Folder 725)
    - Dulles, John Foster, Secretary of State, 1952-1959 (Box 21, Folder 726)
    - Educational and Cultural Instruments of United States Policy, 1962-1986 (Box 21, Folder 727)
    - Eisenhauer Doctrine (Middle East), 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 728)
    - Ethics and American Foreign Policy, 1953-1981 (Box 21, Folder 729)
    - Executive and Foreign Policy, 1964-1972 (Box 21, Folder 730)
    - Executive Privilege, 1959-1974 (Box 21, Folder 731)
    - Executive War Powers: Gulf of Tonkin Resolution, Senate Resolution on Laos, 1951-1973 (Box 21, Folder 732)
    - Foreign Policy Making, 1981-1989 (Box 21, Folder 733)
    - Ideology Defined, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 734)
    - Income and Inflation, 1962-1968 (Box 21, Folder 735)
    - National Interest, 1958-1980 (Box 21, Folder 736)
    - National Security Agency, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 737)
    - National Security Council, including bibliography, 1957-1977 (Box 21, Folder 738)
    - Nationalism and Universalism, articles, 1958-1964 (Box 21, Folder 739)
    - Neutrality and Neutralism, 1940-1965 (Box 21, Folder 740)
    - Official Secrecy, 1959-1982 (Box 21, Folder 741)
    - Peace Corps, 1961-1981 (Box 21, Folder 742)
    - Peace Research, 1971-1983 (Box 21, Folder 743)
    - Political Science 426, I: American Diplomacy, 1620-1801, 1950-1965 (Box 21, Folder 744)
    - Political Science 426, II: The Jeffersonians, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 745)
    - Political Science 426, III: The Jacksonians, undated (Box 21, Folder 746)
    - Political Science 426, IV: 1860-1900, undated (Box 21, Folder 747)
    - Population and Education--Worldwide, 1973-1982 (Box 21, Folder 748)
    - President Richard Nixon and Secretary of State Henry Kissinger in American Foreign Policy, articles, 1973-1982 (Box 21, Folder 749)
    - Pressure Groups and Foreign Policy, 1956-1982 (Box 21, Folder 750)
    - Propaganda: United States Information Service, 1946-1985 (Box 22, Folder 751)
    - Public Opinion, 1949-1990 (Box 22, Folder 752)
    - Races of Mankind, 1946-1970 (Box 22, Folder 753)
    - Research Institutes for Foreign Policy, 1967-1981 (Box 22, Folder 754)
    - State Department: Foreign Service and Embassies, 1960-1983 (Box 22, Folder 755)
    - The Courts and Foreign Policy, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 756)
    - "The Pentagon Papers A Decade Later," by Floyd Abrams of the New York Times, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 757)
    - The Press: It's Relationship to Government; Bias, 1965-1982 (Box 22, Folder 758)
    - Underdeveloped Areas, includes Castleberry lecture, 1965-1966 (Box 22, Folder 759)
    - Underdeveloped Nations, Books on Basic Theory, Articles, 1965-1982 (Box 22, Folder 760)
    - War and United States Policy, 1950-1968 (Box 22, Folder 761)
    - World Food and Health, 1956-1984 (Box 22, Folder 762)
    - World War I and Woodrow Wilson, 1965-1968 (Box 22, Folder 763)
    - World War 11, 1949-1982 (Box 22, Folder 764)
    - Yalta, 1949-1983 (Box 22, Folder 765)
  - Subseries 10.2: Defense Policy
    - Arms Control and Disarmament, 1963-1985 (Box 22, Folder 766)
    - Atlantic Pact, 1958-1982 (Box 22, Folder 767)
    - Civil Defense, 1978-1982 (Box 22, Folder 768)
    - Defense Organization and Policymaking, 19581983 (Box 22, Folder 769)
    - Militarism and the Military-Industrial Complex, 1961-1972 (Box 22, Folder 770)
    - National Security Education, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 771)
    - Nuclear Destruction, Chemical-Bacteriological Warfare and Control Problem, 1955-1969 (Box 22, Folder 772)
    - Nuclear Destruction, Chemical-Bacteriological Warfare and Control Problem, 1968-1984 (Box 22, Folder 773)
    - Selective Service, 1966-1980 (Box 22, Folder 774)
    - Strategic Doctrine, ABM Issue, 1957-1983 (Box 22, Folder 775)
- Series 11: Tape Recordings of Speakers and Lecturers
  - Badeau, John S., President Near East Foundation, Lecture Artist Address. Tape 1, April 22, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 776)
  - Badeau, John S. Tape 2, April 22, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 777)
  - Berger, Elmer, Anti-Zionist Rabbi, March 1, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 778)
  - Berger, Elmer, Tape 2, March 1, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 779)
  - Glubb, General, (Founder of Arab League in Jordan), "Arab Nationalism and International Order,", 1959 (Box 23, Folder 780)
  - Lilienthal, Alfred, "The Middle East--Another Vietnam?", January, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 781)
  - Morgenthau, Hans J., "The Real Issues Between The United States and The U.S.S.R.," talk at Washington State University, December 10, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 782)
  - Sayegh, Fayez, interview by David Suskind, KWSC-TV, January, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 783)